According to the calendar,
按照曆法
this year there are ten days of Navaratri,
今年的女神節共有十天
not of nine.
不是九天
Nine are the days,
九是日數
in the night,
在夜裡
when the Goddess had to fight the demons
女神要對付惡魔
and to save Her children from the effects of negativity.
拯救她的孩子免受邪惡的影響
On one side,
一方面
She was ocean of love and compassion,
她是愛與慈悲的海洋
and on the other side,
另一方面
She was protecting them like a tigress.
她如老虎媽媽般保護她的孩子
Because the times
那時候
were such that nobody could meditate,
沒有人能靜坐
nobody could take the name of God,
也沒有人能唸誦神的名號
nobody could think even of Self-Realisation.
更沒有人能想到自覺
But those who are sitting here today,
可是今天坐在這裡的人
you have been there also in those days,
那時候亦在那兒
and you were all saved for today, for this day,
你們都是為了今天，為了這天而被拯救
so that you can achieve your Self Realisation.
所以你們今天都獲得自覺
The form of the Goddess in those days
那時候，女神並非
was not Maya Swarupi.
以摩耶幻相
She was in Her real form,
而是以她的真身出現
and that created a great awe,
這令人感到極大的敬畏
even among the disciples.
即使她的門徒也對她極之敬畏
So the question of giving them
因此，那時沒法
Self Realisation was not there.
給他們自覺
First of all, they were to be saved.
他們先要被拯救
So like nine months the mother has to keep the child
就像母親要把孩子
in her womb, for these nine months,
保育在子宮內九個月
or you can say nine yugas, nine times,
或說九個時期，九個時分
you all have been saved properly,
你們都恰當的被拯救了
and on the tenth month you are given your birth.
在第十個月出生
Also this birth is always after seven days of nine months.
還有，每次都在九個月又七天後才出生
So we had to wait
我們要等它
for some time till it matures.
成熟
Now the tenth Navaratri today
今天是女神節的第十天
is to celebrate actually the Adi Shakti.
其實是要為太初之母慶祝
So today we are really going to worship the Adi Shakti.
今天其實是要敬拜太初之母
On one side the Adi Shakti is Mahakali,
一方面，太初之母是摩訶迦利
on the other side, She is Mahasaraswati,
另一方面，她是摩訶莎維德麗
in the centre She is Mahalakshmi,
在中央，她是摩訶拉希什米
and also She is the Amba,
亦是安巴(Amba)
the One Who is the Kundalini.
即是靈量
But She is also beyond that.
可是，她也是超越這一切
She's parashakti;
她是parashakti
She's beyond all the powers.
她超越所有力量
Because She is the generator of power.
因為是她製造力量
So, She has to be beyond all that.
所以她必須超越一切
So today when we are worshipping Her,
今天我們敬拜她
we have to worship Her in all these forms.
是要敬拜她的所有形相
So you understand that the tenth day
你們要知道，我們是第一次
that we are having Navaratri for the first time
在曆法上
in the calendar is because
有第十天的女神節
today is the day when we are worshipping Adi Shakti.
因為今天是敬拜太初之母的日子
Adi Shakti was never worshipped before, never.
太初之母從未被敬拜過
But, this time, when I went to Calcutta,
但是，這次當我來到加爾各答
I told them that "You better worship Adi Shakti today."
我告訴他們：「今天最好是敬拜太初之母。」
And they were surprised,
他們都很驚訝
for Adi Shakti to be worshipped?"
要今天敬拜太初之母？
So when I went back to Poona,
當我回到普那
they told Me that Adi Shakti, as you know,
他們告訴我太初之母，如你們所知
is the Saptashringi,
是薩塔施靈基(Saptashringi)
means the One with seven peaks.
即七個山峰
She rests on the seven peaks,
她安頓在七個山峰上
means on the Sahasrara, on the seven, seven chakras.
即在頂輪上，在七個輪穴上
She rules all the seven chakras.
祂掌管全部七個輪穴
They told me that when we had the puja in Calcutta,
他們告訴我，當我們在加爾各答作祟拜時
same time, that's the only time
同一時間，也是唯一一次
when those who follow Saptashringi,
少數追隨
which are very few people, all of them come there,
薩塔施靈基的人來到這裡
and there they come, first of all
他們全都來到這裏
the people from Her mother's side come down.
先是母親那邊的人來到
So the mother's side of the Adi Shakti
太初之母的母親那邊的人
are regarded as Vaishnavites, the one who follow Vishnu.
被稱為Vaishnavites，即追隨毗濕奴的人
So they come first there to worship Her,
他們先來這裏敬拜她
and then the father-in-law's side,
然後是岳父那一邊的人來到
that is Shiva's side, comes in, Sadashiva's side.
即濕婆神的一邊，至高濕婆神的那一邊來到
That's exactly that time when we had the puja.
那剛剛是我們作祟拜的時間
They have these two groups together to worship.
他們兩組人也一起敬拜
So now we have among ourselves people of two types.
我們之中有兩類人
One are, we can call the one who worship Brahmadeva
我們可以稱呼敬拜梵天婆羅摩的人
on the right hand side,
是屬於右邊
Both sides have to meet at a point,
兩者要在某一點相遇
and that point has come,
這一點已經來了
that we have to worship
我們要敬拜
the complete integrated form of all these powers,
這些完全整合狀態的力量
which has manifested within us.
它已經在我們之內彰顯了
Now when they say there is only one God,
當他們說只有一位神
all right there is one God.
對，神只有一位
But one God has got a head,
但是祂有頭顱
He's got His liver,
有肝臟
He's got His stomach,
有胃
He's got His nose.
有鼻子
He's got everything.
祂擁有一切
Just like as human beings are.
就像人類
So then He has different parts in the bodies,
祂身體有不同的部分
and He has to run those different parts.
祂要管理各部分
And for these different parts,
這些不同的部分
He has to have Deities,
要有神祇
and these Deities are to be understood.
我們要了解這些神祇
And unless und until you understand
除非你了解和
you cannot awaken those Deities within yourself.
否則你是不能喚醒你內在的神祇
But they all are part and parcel of the Adi Shakti.
祂們都是太初之母的一部分
Are completely under the control of the Adi Shakti.
完全受太初之母控制
Yesterday you heard about the powers of the Adi Shakti.
昨天你們聽過太初之母的力量
It's like
就像
a tortoise takes his whole body inside his shell,
烏龜把整個身體收入龜殼內
in the same way
同樣
I have withdrawn all these powers within Myself.
我把所有力量收進內裏
I mean, you cannot discover them easily.
我是說你不容易察覺它們
You cannot find them out easily.
不容易把它們找出
Except for these modern cameras,
除了這些現代照相機
which are trying to cheat us.
它想欺騙你們
They are the ones who are giving My forms and things to you.
它們會向你顯露我的不同形相
Because there is light
因為生命能量有光
and when these vibrations are emitted,
當生命能量散發出來
you start seeing them in these cameras,
你會在相機中看到它
even if they may not be very sensitive,
即使它並非很靈敏
but somehow people catch it.
但始終有人會捕捉到它
There have been so many miraculous photographs, as you know.
你們都知道有很多奇蹟的照片
One photograph you must have seen
你必定見過那幀
Now you don't see anyone standing just now here.
現在你不會看到任何人站在這裡
But you don't know what's happening.
也不會知道甚麽在發生
And this is what one has to understand,
我們要明白
That we have entered into a new realm of God's magic.
我們已進入一個神的魔法的新領域
And His magic works, in so many ways.
祂的魔法在很多方面都起作用
Of course, sometimes, you also get lost.
當然，有時你們會迷失
Because of your previous problems you get dragged down.
被過往的問題拉下
You get tempted.
也會受試探
Sometimes you get also dominated
有時候也受
by negative forces and you fall down.
負面力量控制而墜下
And this is a very sad thing
這是發生在任何霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Because perhaps you do not know your past,
或許因為你不知道自己的過去
and you do not know how you have struggled,
不知道自己曾經怎樣掙扎
how you have worked hard to come up to this level.
怎樣努力爭取來到這個層次
And after coming to this level,
來到這個層次後
if you do not try to go higher,
如果你不設法昇進
then
便一是停留在同一個地方
or maybe that you may be thrown down.
一是可能被扔下
So for you to know that you are a Sahaja Yogi,
要知道你的身份是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
you are not a wife, husband, mother, father,
不是妻子、丈夫、母親、父親
you are a Sahaja Yogi.
而是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Like I'm the Adi Shakti,
就像我是太初之母
like that you are Sahaja Yogis.
你是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
So "My main job now is to give realisation to others.
我的主要任務是給人自覺
And because all My relationships are already fixed properly,
因為我的全部親屬都已經安排妥當了
I don't have to worry about any Deity, about any God,
我不用為任何神祇，任何神擔憂
They all work out very efficiently, everything."
祂們都很有效率地成就一切
Now the description yesterday as you read of the Goddess,
你們昨日讀到關於女神的描述
that Her hands were throwing
她用手拋出
all the arrows with such a speed that
利箭的速度快得
as if one felt that She was dancing.
使人以為她在跳舞
Is a fact, no doubt,
這是事實，毋庸置疑
but you don't see that.
只是你看不到
You cannot see that every hair of Mine is like an arrow.
你不會看到我每一根頭髮都像利箭
And it works so tremendously.
它在不斷工作
But to you I'm just sitting here quietly,
對你們來說，我只是像你們那樣
just like you as you are sitting.
靜靜地坐着
But it's not so.
並非如此，事實並非如此
It's something much more.
實際的狀況比這樣多得多
Now when they show a lion or a tiger,
他們看到獅子或老虎
as My vahana,
作為我的坐騎(vahanas)
then you have to understand that they show,
你要明白
actually they are.
你看到
Actually they are.
都是真的
It's not that they are symbolically, actually they are.
牠們並非象徵性，牠們實際就是這般
So the dignity of a tiger,
我曾多次告訴你
I have told you many a times how dignified it is.
老虎是很有威嚴
Because I sit on him, he's so dignified.
因為我騎著牠，牠是很有威嚴
If he has to eat the meat, he'll kill one cow or anything,
如果牠要吃肉，會殺掉一頭牛或任何動物
eat the meat, leave it for others.
只吃掉肉，其他留給別的動物
It's so dignified.
牠是很有尊嚴的
And once a month he eats.
每月只吃一次
So even to get a vahana of this kind,
即使是這樣的坐騎
this was to be evolved from amoeba stage to this stage.
牠也是要從亞米巴蟲進化到現在這個階段
Otherwise he would not have been here.
否則牠不會在這裡出現
In the same way you are evolved,
你們都是這樣子進化而來
and in you are these, all these vahanas also there.
你內在全都有這些，這些坐騎也一樣
And they work out
牠們能快速地
very quickly all that you want.
實現你的要求
You desire something;
當你想得到甚麽
you'll be surprised immediately you'll find it works out.
你會很驚訝你的願望很快實現
You ask for something, immediately it works out.
你的任何要求，能馬上達成
But there should be a complete dedication in Sahaja Yoga.
為此你必須對霎哈嘉瑜伽有完全的虔敬
When I say Sahaj Yog,
當我說到霎哈嘉瑜伽
you know that is the yoga of your attention with My Feet.
你便知道這是你的注意力與我的蓮足的聯合(yoga)
That's what it is.
就是這樣
But if you are still moving with your egos
但是如果你依然充滿自我
and if you are still thinking on those lines
依然有舊有的想法
that "We are something and we can start our own Sahaj Yog,
仍然想：「我們很了不起，我們可以開展自己的霎哈嘉瑜伽
we can work out this way and that way,"
我們可以這麼那麼成就事情
or "My wife is like that, my child is like that,
或「我的妻子像這樣、我的孩子像這樣
my husband is like that."
我的丈夫像這樣
You have to give up all these problems on one side.
你必須擱置這些問題
Otherwise, you will not ascend.
否則，你便不能昇進
It was not difficult for Me to give you Realisation,
給你自覺對我並不困難
because you were just ready for that.
因為你們都準備就緒
But to keep your light on, you have to work hard.
但若你要保持有光，便要努力
Now tiger remains at its own position.
現在老虎仍然守著牠的位置
He doesn't change.
牠沒變
Lion remains at his own position,
獅子也仍然守著牠的位置
and they are all available, all the time,
他們全部都在
in their own position.
自己的位置上隨時候命
All the Devatas and Gods are in Their own positions
所有天將諸神，各有特質
with Their own qualities, They are there.
都在自己的位置上，祂們就在哪裏
Nowhere, none of these Gods have described that
這些諸神，除了女神
They give you moksha. Except for the Goddess.
沒有一位曾被描述能給你解脫
She's the only One who gives you Realisation.
她是唯一一位神祇能給你自覺
Because She's in charge of all the seven chakras.
因為她掌管所有七個輪穴
She holds all these seven chakras,
她掌管這七個輪穴
and on these seven chakras She can work it out.
在這七個輪穴上，她能成就到
So there's a big history,
已經有很長的歷史
evolution of all those things even in the Virata's body,
所有這些都在宇宙大我的身體內進化
and also in you people.
你們也是
So you have to cope with it.
因此你們要處理它
If you cannot cope with it,
若你們不能妥善處理它
then it won't work out.
它便不能成就
Now the problems we have, in the West, as you know,
在西方，你們都知道
are stupid problems
不應在
which are not suitable to any Sahaja Yogi.
任何霎哈嘉瑜伽士身上出現的
Attachment.
愚蠢問題是---依戀
First they were not attached to their wives
之前他們並不依戀妻子
or to their children, now they're attached like glue.
或孩子，現在卻像膠水般纏着他們
I do not say you give up your children or your wife,
不是要你放棄你的孩子，你的妻子
but your attachment should be with Sahaja Yoga.
而是你要依戀黏貼著霎哈嘉瑜伽
Once the blessings of Sahaja Yoga comes to you,
當霎哈嘉瑜伽的祝福降臨你身上
they will flow to your children,
福份自會流往你的孩子
to your wife, to everyone, to your country,
你的妻子、每一人、你的國家
to the whole world.
整個世界
Now supposing this is the attachment,
假如你依戀黏貼著
a very simple electrical thing.
一件很簡單的電器
So if its attachment is not to the mains,
如果它不是插在總電源上
and anywhere else, what's the use?
而是插在其他地方，那有甚麼用？
It cannot give electricity to anybody else.
它不能發電
Is a simple logic,
這是簡單的邏輯
that you should be attached to the source of energy first.
你就是先要接通電源
Simple logic.
簡單的邏輯
And then, that energy can flow to others.
然後，能量便會流向其他人
If you yourself you are not attached
如果你自己並沒有
to that source of energy,
接上能量的源頭
how can that power flow anywhere?
能量又怎能流向其他地方？
It's a simple thing we do not understand in Sahaja Yoga.
這樣簡單，我們在霎哈嘉瑜伽就是不明白
And so our attachments
因此我們的聯繫
start getting rusted and we don't understand
開始生锈，連我們也不明白
what has happened to us.
自己發生了甚麼事
You are not attached to the main source!
你並沒有連上源頭！
And that's the only attachment you need.
那是你唯一需要依戀黏貼的
And then the whole thing will flow to the other end.
那麽全部都會流向盡頭
So, we have these kinds of attachments.
所以，我們要有這種依戀黏貼
Then we are attached to so many miserable things we like,
但我們卻喜歡依戀著很多粗劣的事物
which make us miserable.
這些事物只會令我們痛苦悲傷
For example, we are attached, to say,
例如，我們依戀某些
some sort of a stupid entrepreneur fashion.
可笑的企業家時裝
We're attached to it.
我們依附著它
Whether it is in Sahaj culture or not,
不管它是否霎哈嘉文化
we are attached to it.
我們都依戀着它
And all these attachments are not to the source,
這些執著依戀沒有連上源頭
to the source of joy,
沒有連上喜樂的源頭
to the source of knowledge,
知識的源頭
This is the reason why
這就是
our situation
集體昇進得
of collective ascent is poor.
這麼差勁的原因
Now the Adi Shakti's work is to give you Realisation first,
太初之母的工作是先給你自覺
second is to give you life,
再給你生命
to comfort you.
給你慰藉
If you have physical problems,
如果你有生理的毛病
She will look after you.
她會照顧你
She'll go all out.
會傾盡全力照顧你
If you've mental problem,
如果你有精神的問題
She will try to solve.
她會嘗試助你解決
So, She's a comforter;
所以，她是安慰者
She gives you the comfort.
在給你安慰的同時
At the same time, She protects you.
她亦保護你
I've seen many people, even now,
即使是現在，我看到很多人
get frightened very soon,
會因一些小事
at the slightest thing.
而輕易受驚
Why should you be frightened?
為甚麼要害怕？
There's a tiger standing.
老虎已站在這兒
You can't see him, may be today he might be in the picture.
你看不到牠，或許牠今天在圖像中
And your Mother is so powerful.
你的母親是這麼有力量
You have to understand how powerful She is.
你要明白她是多麼有力量
This is, the understanding is not in your heads.
你的腦海中並沒有這種理解
Sometimes your wives are more powerful
有時候你的妻子是更有力量
or your children are more powerful.
或你的孩子更有力量
When you know that your Mother is so powerful
當你知道你的母親是那麼有力量
- She's your Mother.
她是你的母親
Then you should be absolutely secured.
你應該感到非常安全
And then things work out.
那麽事情便會成就到
I'll give you an example of one gentleman
舉一個例子，有一個男士
whom I met in Madras
約兩、三年前
once, not many years back,
我在印度
about I think two, three years back or so.
馬德拉斯遇過
He was such a seeker, immediately he recognized Me.
他是求道者，他馬上認出我
And then he went down to Bombay, posting was there,
之後他被調派到孟買工作
and he received a letter saying that his mother
在接到他的母親病得很重的信件後
on death bed. So he went down.
他趕去探望她
The doctor said that "She has a galloping cancer
醫生說：「她患上急性癌症
and she's going to die in no time."
快要死了
He knows, "My Mother is Adi Shakti."
他知道：「我的母親是太初之母。」
Just took My photograph, sat before Me,
他坐在我照片前說
said, "Mother, I've nothing to say,
母親，我沒有甚麼要說
whatever You think proper for my mother, please do that."
請你做任何你認為對我媽媽合適的事情
Just he said so. He's connected.
單單這麼說，他就連上了
They said three days after, "She's going to die."
他們說三天後，「她快要死了。」
Three days after she got out of the hospital.
三天後她出院了
He took him down to Bombay, showed him in a hospital,
他帶她到孟買，
in cancer hospital.
到治癌症的醫院
They said, "She has no cancer, nothing,
他們說：「她沒有癌症，
she's completely cured."
她痊癒了
If the energy is not allowed to flow,
假如不讓能量流通…
you are still worried about your wife,
你仍然擔心你的妻子
you're worried about your house,
你的房子
you're worried about your children,
你的孩子
you're worried about this,
擔心
about "my children, my house, my wife"
我的孩子，我的房子，我的妻子…
this "my" when it drops,
當你能放棄這個「我」，我便能工作
But it should not be taken
我不是說
No saints were ascetics,
沒有聖人是苦行者
they all had wives, they all had children.
他們全都有妻子，有孩子
But all their attention was at the Lotus Feet of the Mother.
可是他們的注意力都放在母親的蓮足上
As Guru Nanaka has said
導師拿納克曾說
that a little boy is playing with his kite,
一個小男孩在放風箏
the kite is going all over,
風箏在天上飛的同時
and he is talking to his friends, joking, this thing,
他跟友人談天說笑，
but his attention is on the kite.
可是他的注意力仍放在風箏上
There's a lady who is cleaning her house
有一個女士清潔她的房子
with a little child on her waist,
她的腰間繫着一個小孩
and she's cleaning the house and grooming it.
她清潔打掃屋子
She's doing everything, but her attention is on her child.
做各種事情，但她的注意力仍是放在孩子身上
Then there are ladies in India, as you know,
在印度有些婦女，你都知道
they have three, four pitchers filled water
她們扛着三、四個盛滿水的缸
and they walk with both the hands like this.
而她們走路時雙手是這樣子的
They know how to balance it.
她們知道怎樣平衡
They're talking to each other, laughing, making fun,
她們談天說笑，互相嘲弄
pulling legs. But the attention is on the pitchers.
但注意力仍是放在水缸上
My attention is always on your Kundalini.
我的注意力常常放在你的靈量上
You cannot play tricks in Sahaja Yog, take it from Me.
你不能在霎哈嘉瑜伽玩把戲，要聽信我
Anybody who tries to play any trick
任何人想玩把戲
will be very badly punished.
都會受到很大的懲罰
So please be very, very careful not to be dishonest,
所以請你們要非常非常小心，不要不誠實
and not to play tricks in Sahaja Yoga.
不要在霎哈嘉瑜伽玩把戲
I won't do anything, but here they are!
我不會做甚麽，牠們卻會！
You see already, with all his teeth.
你已經看到…牠的牙齒
They're all fixed quantities, I have told them.
牠們都有特定的素質，我告訴了牠們
They're are fixed quantities.
牠們都有特定的素質
They know what to do, and they will do it.
知道該怎樣做，而牠們是會付緒實行的
So there is no need to play any tricks in Sahaja Yoga.
因此，沒有需要在霎哈嘉瑜伽玩把戲
This is another mistake of Sahaja Yogis,
霎哈嘉瑜伽士犯的另一個錯誤
that they think they can play tricks with Me
就是以為可以向我或
When those things come into your head,
當這些魔鬼的念頭
I would say these are demonic ideas,
出現在你的腦海中
because they will destroy you completely.
它們會完全摧毀你
On one side Sahaja Yoga is a blessing,
一方面霎哈嘉瑜伽是一種祝福
absolutely blessing on the ascent you go ahead like that.
對你的昇進絕對是祝福
You go to a height,
你到達某個高度
but you must know also, you've reached the height;
但你也要知道，當你到達某個高度
because once you fall from that height,
因為一旦你從這高度跌下
how deep you'll go?
你會跌得多深？
Is logical again to see that you'll fall very low.
可想而知你會跌得很低很重
So here you are having the blessings,
在這兒你享有祝福
all the beauties, all the love, all the joy,
所有美麗的事物、愛、喜樂
all the knowledge, all the friends, all the care.
知識、朋友、關懷
And there, if you don't want to be here,
在這兒，若你不想留在這兒
just because you are playing tricks,
只要玩把戲就可以了
you want to be here and play tricks, that is not possible.
若你想既留在這裡又玩把戲，是不可能的
That doesn't work out,
是不會成功的
you are immediately thrown out,
你會馬上被踢走
and once you are thrown out, God knows where you'll go.
一旦你被踢走，天曉得你會到那兒
but you are thrown out by these.
你會因此被踢走
So one has to know that the Deities are extremely alert.
我們要知道諸神是非常有醒覺性的
And They're watching all of you.
祂們觀察着你們所有人
Because They have to guard you,
因為祂們要指引你
They have to look after you,
照顧你
They have to help you,
幫助你
They have to do everything for you.
為你做各種事情
They have to work out everything for you.
成就一切
They are the Ones who create flowers for you;
祂們為你創造花兒
They're doing all kinds of good things for you.
為你做所有的好事情
But, at the same time,
可是同時
They are only attached to Me,
祂們全都只會
all of Them,
黏貼依戀着我
not to you.
不是你
Because you are My children,
因為你是我的孩子
They are looking after you.
所以祂們照顧你
Once you try to misbehave,
當你行為不當
you are finished and you go down.
就會完蛋和下跌
But the compassion of your Mother is so great,
可是你母親的愛是那麼偉大
that She always tries to forgive,
她常常都寬恕
give chances and tells those Deities to keep quiet.
給予機會，叫諸神不要作出任何行動
Of course They obey - up to a point.
當然，祂們只會服從到某一限度
But if you want to be nasty people,
若你想做下流
if you want to be cruel,
殘忍
if you want to be sinful
邪惡的事情而
and stay in Sahaja Yoga, you cannot.
同時又留在霎哈嘉瑜伽，你不能
It's not like any religion as you saw yesterday
這不像你昨日看到的任何宗教
that you commit any mistakes,
你犯錯
and still be there.
仍然能留下
It's not like that.
不像這樣
Here you have to be Sahaja Yogi
在這裡你要成為真正的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
in the real sense of the word.
這一點你們要明白的
And this is why one has to understand.
所以我們要明白...
There are some Sahaja Yogis have come, they can't get in,
有些霎哈嘉瑜伽士來了，他們進不了來
I think the doors are closed.
門應該關上了
So, now such a tremendous Power,
這個力量是那麼強大
so alert, so affectionate,
那麼警覺，那麽充滿愛心
And a Mother, Who is your teacher.
既是母親又是你的導師
Mother teaches children with love.
母親以愛心去教導孩子
Not only that,
不單如此
but you never even felt how I taught you Sahaja Yoga.
你永遠不感到我在教導你霎哈嘉瑜伽
You just learnt it like that.
你就是這樣學懂了
It's a child's play for you.
像小孩玩遊戲般就學會了
It's such a difficult and subtle subject;
這個既深奧又精微的課題
you picked it up without any difficulties.
你輕而易舉就學懂了
So artfully it was done,
很巧妙地
beautifully it was done,
美麗地完成了
built in within you, now you know this is Sahaja Yog,
你內在已裝設好。現在你知道這是霎哈嘉瑜伽
this is not Sahaj Yoga.
這不是霎哈嘉瑜伽
All this knowledge came to you so sweetly.
全部知識都那麼甜美地給予你
The way you sing Indian musics, you see,
你們唱印度歌曲的樣子，你知道嗎
even the Indians are surprised,
連印度人也感到驚訝
they can't sing like you sometimes.
他們有時也不能唱得像你們那樣
Those who had come to My programme, they saw you.
那些來我的講座的人
Some musicians, they said,
一些音樂家，他們看見你們，說：
"We were really ashamed.
我們真的很慚愧
How could these people sing so well?
這些人怎能唱得這麼好？
And pronounce everything so well?"
發音這麼準確？
And you have to trust this Power fully.
你要完全信賴這力量！
Those days, when people were in difficulties,
那時，他們遇到困難
they were always attacked,
常常受打擊
they had not got their Self Realisation,
他們仍未得到自覺
they had to put their trust into the Divine Power.
他們要常常依靠這個神聖的力量
They had to put.
他們必須要這樣
But now when you have got Realisation,
現在你們都已得到自覺
you have got your freedom.
都已獲得自由
Should never forget that you have to trust
但仍不要忘記信賴
this Divine Power.
這個神聖的力量
All the time that It will look after you.
它每時每刻都在照顧你們
Now, how do we play tricks in Sahaja Yoga?
他們怎樣在霎哈嘉瑜伽玩把戲？
Some lazy lumps come into Sahaja Yoga.
有些懶骨頭來到霎哈嘉瑜伽
Absolute lazy lumps, means they must be left-sided
絕對是懶骨頭，他們一定是偏左脈
or whatever it is.
不管如何
And if you tell them, "You better do this work."
如果你告訴他
"No Mother, I won't do this work,
不，母親，我不能做這工作
because my right side will come up."
不然我會偏右脈
Very common trick.
這是很常見的把戲
Is a very common trick,
常見的把戲是
"I can't do this work!"
我不能做這工作
How many people work?
有多少人願意工作？
Very few.
很少
The other day I went to the kitchen,
那天我走進廚房
and I asked this Indian girls what's happening,
我問那個印度女孩發生了甚麼事
Nobody's here to help us."
沒有人留下幫忙
Nobody wants to take responsibility.
沒有人想擔起責任
But the trick is that it is played on Sahaja Yoga,
在霎哈嘉瑜伽的把戲是這樣的
that "If I do this thing I will become right-sided."
如果我做這工作，我會偏向右脈
But if you become left-sided,
但是如果你偏向左脈
this one is there.
牠就在這兒
Is very nice you have put him here, I am very happy.
把牠放在這兒很好，我很高興
So, all lethargic people, lazy lumps,
所有怠倦散慢的人，懶骨頭
always do that.
常常都是這樣
Now, somebody is told that
有些人被勸說
"You have to get up in the morning."
你要早起
They feel terrible about it,
他們感到早起是很糟的
"Oh! How to get up?"
噢！怎能起床呀？
But if you go back into your own background,
但是當你想想你的過去
you'll say you must have taken drugs,
你一定曾經吸毒
you must have taken alcohols,
酗酒
you must have taken all these left-sided things,
吸食一切左脈的東西
that's why you cannot get up in the morning!
那是你不能早起的原因！
Now, how will you
現在，你該如何
finish or neutralize those bad habits that you had?
戒掉或中和這些壞習慣？
How will you do it?
你應怎樣做？
If you start getting up early in the morning,
如果你開始早起
slowly the habit will be formed,
慢慢便能養成習慣
and you can get rid of it.
壞習慣自能戒除
It's just to make yourselves available
讓自己迎接
when the morning sun is about to come.
清晨的陽光
Alcohol itself is such a left-sided nonsense.
酒精是很左脈的垃圾
So much so that once the Goddess drank
即使女神亦曾經
all the alcohols of the world.
喝掉全世界的酒精
You won't believe, all the alcohols!
你不會相信，所有酒精！
Saints like Sainath smoked all the tobacco of Maharastra,
聖人如賽巴巴曾抽光馬哈拉斯特拉邦的煙草
but still they are smoking.
但他們仍然吸煙
Like Shiva drank the whole of the poison
濕婆神把毒液喝光
because He is the giver of life.
因為祂是生命的賜予者
Whatever They have worked so much,
祂們很真誠
so sincerely,
誠懇
earnestly with complete concentration.
全神貫注的做了很多工作
You see Me working like that,
你看我也是這樣工作
but They have also worked the same way.
祂們也曾這樣工作
So don't take things for granted!
因此，不要視一切為理所當然！
I have told many of you to write down,
我曾經叫你們寫下
what have I done for Sahaja Yoga today?
自己今天為霎哈嘉瑜伽做了些甚麼？
For myself I'll do everything - I'll paint my house,
我會為自己做各種事情---我會為自己的屋子
I'll paint my kitchen, everything,
和廚房漆上顏色，做一切的事情
I'll have a nice sari done up, blouse done up.
我會裁好一件漂亮的紗麗，也做好上衣
Myself.
那麽
What have I done for Sahaja Yoga?
我為霎哈嘉瑜伽做了些甚麼？
How many presents I have given to others?
我送了多少禮物給人？
How many letters I've written to others?
我寫了多少封信給人？
What experiences I have written down?
我寫下自己的多少經驗？
Above all,
最重要的是
how many times I have felt the love of my Mother in my heart?
我有多少次在心裡感受母親的愛？
But I'll tell you the reason in the West
我要告訴你
why the big problem is, I've discovered it now.
西方一個很大的問題，我現在才發現
As I discovered Sahaja Yoga,
當我發現霎哈嘉瑜伽
also I've discovered the secret
我亦同時發現
which I am telling you today.
今天我要告訴你的秘密
This is also the Shakti of penetration
女神力量的滲透力
that one can find out the demons,
使人可以找出惡魔
how they work in our minds,
它們是怎樣在我們的思維中運作
how they prosper.
怎樣繁衍昌盛
I think I've told some people,
我曾經告訴一些人
but I am going to tell you all.
我會告訴所有人
When we are children,
當我們還是小孩時
till the age of five years,
直到五歲
we are ego-oriented
我們都是自我中心
in the sense that we are just looking after ourselves.
的只顧自己
You give ten toys to ten children,
你把十件玩具給十個孩子
they'll take their toys and play with each other,
他們只會拿了玩具一起玩
don't talk to anyone, they'll just go and play.
不會與任何人說話，只會玩
They'll not disturb another one,
不會騷擾其他人
it's all parallel living.
各自生活
They won't disturb.
互不騷擾
If they disturb, they might beat,
如果他們受騷擾，便可能會打人
they might do something else nonsensical.
可能會做一些荒謬的事情
This might be due to some sort of a bhoot in them
原因可能是有某些小孩的亡靈
as children.
附著他們
But when they are five years of age,
但當他們五歲大
supposing now, you ask somebody, a child from here,
就如現在你問任何一個在這裏的孩子
"See now, what do you see?"
現在你看到甚麼？
He says, "I see a tiger here, and these flowers,
他說：「我看到老虎，看到花朵
this, this, all this I see."
看到這些那些，我看到這些
But if you make him stand there,
但如果你要他站在哪兒
supposing somebody's standing that side,
假設有人站在那邊
what will he see? Still he will say he sees tiger,
他會看到甚麼？他仍然會說看到老虎
Because he cannot see the point of view of another person.
試試吧。因為他不會從另一個人的角度去看事物
He's just busy with his ego.
他只是忙著應付自己的自我
Now the whole culture in the West, I have found now
整個西方文化，我現在發現
- I don't know, formally it was not so,
我也不清楚，過往不是這樣的
parents had a great grip over the children,
父母看管得孩子很緊
and they had responsibility of children,
他們對孩子有責任感
Not like before the children they go on fighting with each other.
和以前不同，孩子們
I mean, they must be fighting little bit,
他們有時會打架
but in the bedrooms they must be doing.
但只限在睡房內
Because I have not seen films, when I was young,
我年輕時沒有看
where the husband/wife are only all the time fighting,
夫婦時常吵架
or going for divorce.
鬧離婚的電影
No, at all, understanding between husband and wife,
完全沒有。夫婦之間的了解不是這樣子的
but when it is another woman or another man,
但若是另一個女人或男人
their face is going like this.
他們的臉孔會變成這樣
If you see on the street
如果你在街上
two people going with each other like this,
看到兩個人像這樣走在一起
then you know these two are not husband and wife.
你便知道他們不是夫婦
This is modern times.
這是現代
These are modern times.
這就是現代
And the West is the worst.
西方是最差的
So what happens that the parents are also not grown up,
連父母也未成長
they are not matured, they have no sense of responsibility.
未成熟，完全沒有責任感
They have got children, how to behave with the husband,
他們有孩子，怎樣與丈夫相處
specially the women here are extremely,
特別是這裡的婦女是
extremely dominating and stupid.
又專制又愚蠢
I must say.
我可以說
They don't know anything about cooking;
她們對烹飪一竅不通
they don't know anything about anything.
甚麼都不懂…任何事
They can only career girls, they can go,
她們只會送信，
sit in the bank and write something.
在銀行做抄寫
And they're extremely stupid;
她們極之愚蠢
they don't know how to handle their husbands,
不懂怎樣與丈夫相處
they don't know how to handle their children.
與孩子相處
They have had no training.
她們沒有受過訓練
Their mother's paid no attention to them.
她們的母親沒有關懷她們
No disciplining at all.
對她們完全沒有紀律
So this-ego oriented child is still ego-oriented.
因此，這些自我中心的孩子仍舊是自我中心
No love, no affection.
沒有愛，沒有感情
We would say My Mother was a very strict person.
我們可以說我的母親是非常嚴格的人
Extremely strict.
極之嚴格
But she was extremely loving also - extremely loving,
但同時她也極之有愛心---非常有愛心
I mean, she would make us cook food,
她教我們煮食
even the handle how you hold.
即使怎樣拿手柄她都會教
She would tell us, "This is not the angle,
她會告訴我們：「不是這個角度
it's not the way, you do this way!
這樣不成，這樣才成
Why are you standing like this?
為甚麼你這樣子站着？
Where is your attention?"
你的注意力在哪兒？
And no questions were to be asked.
不准提問
All that disciplining and all that thing
這些我們童年時
which came to us in our childhood is today helpful to us.
學懂的紀律對我們今天很有用
And they were extremely loving.
還有是他們極之有愛心
They were for our benevolence,
無論他們做任何事
whatever they did were for our benevolence.
都是為了我們的福祉
But I think, specially in Switzerland,
可是我認為，尤其是在瑞士
I always felt that the mothers are uneducated
我經常感到那些母親是沒有受過敎育的
and they're extremely jealous of their daughters also.
她們連自己的女兒也非常妒忌
Our mothers, My mother was very well educated,
我們的母親…我的母親受過很好的教育
but her mother was not.
可是她的母親卻並非如此
But she was a wise woman.
她有智慧
She had her sense of responsibility,
有責任感
she knows she was a mother
她知道自己是位母親
and she has to behave herself.
所以言行必須檢點
She has not to be childish and stupid.
不能孩子氣和愚蠢
So because that love was not given to these ladies,
因為這些女士沒有得到愛
they are still ego-oriented.
所以她們仍然自我中心
They're still babies.
仍然是嬰兒
They're not yet grown up.
仍然未成長
Still they cannot see the other person's point of view
仍然未能從他人的角度去看事情
and they become extremely obstinate:
而且變得非常固執
"No, this is true!"
不，這是真的！
Now let us face it,
讓我們現在面對它吧
today you have had this Puja of Adi Shakti,
今天的太初之母祟拜
is a dangerous one,
是很危險的
because this is like a mirror
因為它像一面鏡子
clearly, face yourself.
面對自己
To dominate your husband is a stupid nonsense.
宰制丈夫是件愚蠢的事
Because you don't know
原因是你不懂
I would say Indian women dominate
我可以說印度婦女在某程度上
their husbands all right, in a way.
宰制她們的丈夫是可以的
The husbands can't do without their wives,
丈夫不能沒有妻子
can't do without their wives.
不能沒有妻子
They don't know even how to pack their things,
他們甚至連怎樣收拾東西
they don't know how to even make tea,
怎樣弄茶
they don't know how to boil an egg,
怎樣煮熟一只蛋都不懂
they don't know anything.
他們甚麼都不懂
They don't know even how to lock the house,
怎樣鎖門開門
how to spread a bed.
怎樣鋪床也不懂
They don't know anything whatsoever that is practical.
任何務實的事情他們都不懂
I mean I would say that
我的意思是
my husband would always come and ask Me,
我丈夫經常來問我
"Is this tie all right?"
這領帶行嗎？
but before also.
雖然過往也是
He used to come and ask,
他習慣來問：
"Is it all right?" "No, no it's no good."
「這個好嗎？」「不，這個不好。」
All right, he would change.
他便會更換
But because you are not grown up,
因為你們仍未成長
you are not matured,
仍未成熟
you don't know how to handle your husbands.
你不懂怎樣與丈夫相處
You try to dominate.
你想去宰制人
And then the children learn from you,
孩子也有樣學樣
they also try to dominate you.
他們也宰制你
Apparently, you must understand,
表面上，你要明白
it is
這權力是從上而來的
Like I always will say,
像我常常說：
Gregoire was quiet shocked when I told him first this thing.
當我這樣告訴葛雷瓜時，他感到很震驚
But I am God also.
我也是神
Without Me what is He? I'm His Power.
沒有我，祂是誰？我是祂的力量
He's powerless.
祂並沒有力量
But let Him be God, good.
讓祂成為神好了
Because if you have to blame someone,
因為如果你要怪責任何人
you blame Him, He's God.
你可以怪責祂。祂是神
But I have to work hard to keep Him pleased.
我要努力工作去取悅祂
Otherwise you know, He doesn't care for anyone.
否則，你也知道，祂不會理會任何人
He'll just destroy, that's all He knows.
只會毀滅，祂只懂毀滅
He'll destroy you,
任何人想向我玩把戲
anybody tries to play any tricks with Me,
祂會毀滅你
you cannot become a human being.
令你很多世也不能成為人類
He's like that, a terrible fellow.
祂就是那樣子，可怕的傢伙
He's the One Who has done all these things, you know.
你要知道，這種事都是祂做的
So, we have to grow.
因此，我們要成長
We have to grow as wise women,
我們要成長成有智慧的女性
as women who are like the Mother Earth, as I told you.
因為，正如我告訴你，女性就像大地之母
And when you ask me that
當你問我：
"Mother, You work so hard, and You look so fresh."
母親，你工作得這麼辛勞，但看來仍然容光煥發
Because I enjoy it.
因為我享受
It's like a music to Me.
對我來說那是音樂
Doing work is a music to Me.
工作對我來說是音樂
Cooking is a music to Me.
煮食對我來說也是音樂
Everything is a music to Me.
所有的事情對我來說都是音樂
Do you get tired of music?
你會不會討厭音樂？
On the contrary you feel fresh.
相反你感到很清新
And when I kill demons,
你都看到，
I get more enlightened, more light comes into Me.
我變得更覺醒，擁有更多光
It's the other way round.
情況是剛剛相反
So, I have to make you understand that
我要你們明白
today please have full introspection,
今天請你內省
soul search.
作靈魂的搜尋
Find out what's wrong with us.
找出自己出甚麼問題
Do not pamper your ego,
不要縱容你的自我
because ego makes you idiotic,
因為自我令你變蠢
that you must have seen.
這是你一定要看到的
We have some people in Sahaja Yoga
在霎哈嘉瑜伽有些人
who are like that, idiots.
是那麼愚蠢
But they think knowing of themselves.
只顧自己
We all know that.
我們都知道
We have to have some buffoons also in the circus.
馬戲班要有小丑
But we have to have lions and tigers.
也要有獅子和老虎
What impresses the people are the lions and the tigers
但令人着迷的是獅子和老虎
and not the buffoons.
並非小丑
So, it is important, let us have the introspection
要內省，看看自己為
and see for ourselves
霎哈嘉瑜伽
how much we have done for Sahaja Yoga.
做了些甚麼，這是很重要的
Of course, I have to congratulate you for one thing.
當然，有一件事我要恭喜你
Because, you know, I am like that.
因為我就是這樣
I have done nothing to be like that, I'm just like that,
我沒有做過甚麼變成這樣，我就是這樣
I am.
我是
So I'm the Power!
我就是力量
If I have the Power, because I am the Power.
如果我擁有力量，只因為我就是力量
What is there to feel very elated about it?
那又有甚麼值得興奮呢？
I do not feel that way at all.
我一點也沒有這種感覺
But if I do not use My Power,
但如果我不運用我的力量
then I become like a human being.
我就如人類一般
Why I am the Goddess?
為甚麼我是女神？
Because I use every bit of My Power.
因為我能運用我擁有的一分一毫的力量
And if you people do not use your power,
如果你們因為一些廢話
out of any nonsense, any fear you may have.
恐懼而不使用你的力量
You may have any kind of a temptation,
又或因為任何誘惑
or restriction, anything.
任何限制，或類似的事情
If you're not going all out to use your power of love,
而不盡力去使用你愛的力量
then you cannot ascent.
便不能昇進
So the whole thing if you see so clearly,
若你看清楚
the whole Power of your Mother is of love.
母親的整個力量是愛
Whatever She does is out of Her love for Her creation.
她做任何事都是源於她愛她的創造物
And the introspection starts,
要反省
but it should not be late.
但不要太遲
I used to say since long
我很久以前也常說
the way they are exhausting the Mother Earth,
他們製造這麼多物品
making so many things.
正消耗大地之母的資源
You must have heard Me saying this,
你一定聽過我這樣說
for the last eighteen years I've been saying this.
十八年來，我都重覆說著這番話
Today now ecological problems
現在生態問題
standing like a rakshasa before you.
像一個惡魔站在你的面前
Now what do you do with him?
你有甚麼對策？
So you face then.
你只能面對它
Automatically you have to face yourself, your destruction.
你自然就能面對自己，面對自己的毀滅
Introspection, if you do not do now,
內省，如果你不馬上內省
you'll face it at a time when it will be very late.
當再面對它時便會太遲了
So don't be just satisfied with yourself,
所以不要單單滿足於自己
that you have now Sahaja Yogi, so done.
滿足於你已成為霎哈嘉瑜伽士就可以了
If you have come to My Puja of course,
如果你來我的崇拜
like if you fall into the sea,
就像你跌進海洋裏
the sea has a power to absorb you.
海洋有能力吞噬你
But also has a power to throw you back on the shores.
也有能力把你拋回岸上
It acts both ways.
海洋在這兩方面都能起作用
So why can't I go deep into Sahaja Yoga?
為甚麼我未能在霎哈嘉瑜伽深化？
There are excuses also: I have got no time, I am very busy,
藉口多多：我沒有時間、我很忙
I am working in the office, I am doing that.
我要工作等等，我正在做
Then you are not a Sahaja Yogi.
那麽你便不是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
All your time is for Sahaja Yoga.
你的全部時間都是為了霎哈嘉瑜伽
But because of that,
因為這緣故
Sahaja Yoga gives you sufficient time to do everything.
霎哈嘉瑜伽給你充足時間去做其他事情
I know of people,
我不時
whom I suddenly find in the Pujas,
在溫哥華
sometimes in Vancouver, sometimes in San Diego,
聖地牙哥，或在這兒的崇拜
sometimes here.
遇見一些人
I said, "How are you here, what about your business?"
我問：「你怎麼來了，你的生意怎辦？」
He said, "The business has brought us here,
他說：「我正是為了生意來這兒
exactly on this date."
正好在這天
When this Power is so great, to realise it,
當你領會了解
to know how great it is,
這力量有多偉大
then you leave everything to this Power.
你就會把所有事情交托給這力量
It works out for you everything.
它為你解決所有事情
So today we are talking about Shakti,
今天我會談到力量(Shakti)
about the Power of the Goddess,
女神的力量
which are much more to be discovered
我們仍未對它完全了解
and too intricate,
它是很精密
very well balanced and extremely efficient.
很平衡和極之有效率的
But whatever work these Powers have done within you,
無論這些力量為你做了些甚麼
please try to respect them.
請你尊重它們
Please, try to assimilate them,
請儘量吸收它們
and let your being grow.
好讓自己成長
Don't say that "Now I'm married,"
不要說：「我結婚了，」
or that "I've got pregnancy,"
或「我懷孕了，」
Everything becomes perfect,
當你變得完美
as soon as you perfect yourself.
所有事都會變得完美
Everything is related to your perfection.
所有事情都連繫到你有多完美
Then you don't ask Me question,
然後，你不再問我
"What job I have to do Mother,
母親，我要做甚麼工作
what I have to achieve?"
我要成就甚麼？
Nothing.
不是這樣
You just see your way through and everything works out.
你看到自己的路，萬事都會成就
So, all the demons were killed,
所有從前被殺掉的
they are again back in their own seats.
惡魔又重回他們的原來的位置
The worst thing is they have entered
最壞的是他們以
into the heads of the seekers,
導師的身份
because they have come as gurus now.
進入求道者的腦袋
They've come as Catholic Church,
他們化身為天主教
as Protestant Church,
基督教
as all kinds of temples
各種廟宇和各種
All they look like rakshasas also,
若你看看他們
if you look at them.
他們看來就像惡魔
And when they influence you, they go into your heads.
當你受他們影響，他們便會進入你們的腦海中
But after coming to Sahaja Yoga,
當你來到霎哈嘉瑜伽
even those heads are cleansed
腦袋被潔淨
and you are all right, out of it.
你回復正常
But then what to do with this,
跟著要怎樣
with doing all this work,
做甚麽工作
cleansing, and giving joy, and everything, then what to do?
在潔淨自己、傳播喜悅的同時，還要做甚麼？
You have to give it to others!
你要把它給予別人
This is your responsibility.
這是你的責任
So first of all your character, your behaviour,
首先，你們的個性、行為
your relationships should be so pure
關係要純潔到
that, by itself, it will emit light.
可以發光
Like if you have a very clean glass,
就如一塊很清潔的玻璃
the light can pass.
光才能通過
But also, Kundalini being the pure desire,
但是，靈量作為純粹的欲望
you must have a very fervent and extremely bubbling,
你要很殷切熱烈，要像泉湧般的
you can call it a absolutely pouring out desire
欲望去給人生命能量
whom to give vibrations, now, whom to give realisation.
那麽，給誰自覺
You give it to the trees,
你把自覺給予樹木
you give it to the dogs, you give it to anyone,
給予狗兒、給予任何人
and if you find human beings also give them.
你也可以給予人類
Rather difficult.
雖然是頗困難
So, that has to be done.
一定要這樣做
But whatever you are doing,
無論你作何事
But here they are doing Sahaja Yoga,
在做霎哈嘉瑜伽的工作的時候
and there your connection is loose,
如果你的聯繫是很鬆散的
then what you are giving? Sahaja Yog or what?
你在給予別人甚麼？霎哈嘉瑜伽還是其他？
You are giving darkness?
你在給人黑暗？
Your are giving ignorance.
給人無明
You are giving madness.
給人瘋狂
So, to this powerful Shakti
所以，每時每刻
you must all the time keep connection, and keep Her pleased.
你都要與這個強大的力量保持連繫，讓它高興
Like the protocol
禮法是非常重要的
is very important because all these you see.
因為你看看這裏…
They have the protocol sense, because They are fixed.
牠們都懂禮法，因為牠們是固定的
You should also fix your protocol properly.
你們也應該好好地牢記禮法
what should be the protocol of the Goddess. Really.
女神的禮法確是頗為困難尷尬
But the protocol must be observed
你一定要遵守禮法
and could be understood very well.
充分了解禮法
Of course, it's much better now.
當然，現在已好多了
First time they had My Puja, in Delhi,
在德里第一次為我做崇拜時
they did My aarti with a plastic plate,
他們用膠碟來做搖燈禮
and the kum-kum was kept in plastic boxes,
用膠盒子盛載紅粉
and I was so much worried about these people
那時我很替他們擔憂
"Now don't do anything!"
甚麼也不要做！
If you see My photograph you'll see Me very different.
如果你看到我的照片，會發覺我看來很不同
I was so surprised they didn't know what to do.
我很驚訝他們不知要怎樣做
All right, now, please also
好吧，現在請你們注意禮法
For example people walk just early in the morning
就如有人在早晨
in their pyjamas, that's not proper.
穿著睡衣四處走，這是不恰當的
You must dress up properly.
你們要穿戴得恰當
You're going, you don't know what Adi Shakti is.
你正要…你知不知道太初之母是誰？
Or you know?
又或你知道甚麽？
If you know then you are going to face Adi Shakti.
如果你知道要與太初之母見面
Protocol must be understood.
一定要明白禮法
For that, luckily, in India, people have lot of sense;
幸好，在印度，人們很懂事
also they are sometimes missing in it.
雖然他們有時也會犯錯
So, protocol is very important
禮法是很重要的
because These will be really furious
若你不遵守禮法
That is extremely important.
這是極之重要的
That's why Christ has said
這就是基督為甚麽說︰
He'll "tolerate anything against Myself,
祂能容忍不利於祂的一切
but nothing against the Holy Ghost."
卻不能容忍任何不利於聖靈的
And also He has said that,
他亦說：
"Beware of the murmuring souls"
當心喃喃終日的靈
because if you murmur on My back, I hear everything.
因為若你在我背後竊竊私語，我全都聽到
They're reporting all the time.
他們隨時向我報告
If you do anything on My back, I know what's happening.
我知道所有你在我背後做的事情
I give time. But then it acts.
我會給你時間，然後它就會作出行動
It's for your benevolence, for your good,
這是為你着想，為你的好處
for your ascent for which you have fought for ages!
為你歷世爭取的昇進
and now you have found out the truth.
你現在已經找到真理
So, make a crown out of it,
用真理做一個王冠
and put it on your head.
戴在頭上吧
Now you are like lords.
你就像王者
Unless and until
除非你知道
you know what powers you have and how you got them,
自己擁有甚麼力量、知道怎樣取得它
and you remember it,
還要緊記它
and also this truth becomes part and parcel of you,
讓真理成為你的一部分
your growth is going to be difficult.
否則你便很難成長
You'll be neither here nor there,
你不是在這裏就是在那裏
hanging in the air like a pendulum going here to there,
只會像鐘擺般在半空中
left to the right, right to the left.
不斷盪來盪去
And a Sahaja Yogini should be ashamed to say
女霎哈嘉瑜伽士會因為說了：
that "I'll go on the left, or I'll go on the right."
「我會偏向左面，或我會偏向右面」而感到羞愧
How can you be so vulnerable?
你怎能這麼不堪一擊？
Because you have not grown.
只因你仍未成長
You have to be like Rock of Gibraltar.
你要像直布羅陀石(Rock of Gibraltar)
How can you catch?
你怎會受感染？
All right, if you think somebody is extremely negative,
好吧，如果你認為某人極之負面
don't go near that person.
不要走近他
But you cannot become a dainty darlings.
這樣你只是不能成為乖巧的寶貝
My children are viras, shivalrous.
我的孩子一定要
They have to be.
成為正直的勇者
You are My children.
你是我的孩子
You are no more Christians, Hindus, Muslims,
不再是基督徒、印度教徒、穆斯林
you are no more all these horrible demonic people,
不再是可怕邪惡的人
but you are My children and you have to be brave,
你是我的孩子，你要勇敢
you have to be righteous,
正義
you have to be good, you have to be compassionate,
善良、有愛心
you have to be dynamic.
有活力，那是最起碼的
I hope after this Puja you'll sit down,
我希望你們在崇拜後，坐下
meditate and do introspection,
靜坐和內省
and find out, "Why I do it? What is the problem?"
找出：「我為何這樣做？問題出在哪兒？」
Say, some people yesterday were dozing off, I saw them.
昨天我看到有些人在打盹，這是因為
Because of left Nabhi.
左臍輪的問題
So correct your left Nabhi.
因此，要清理你的左臍輪
But if you are really connected with this Divine Power,
如果你與上天的力量完全連上
you may keep awake for three days and three nights,
三天三夜不睡覺也不會
you'll not be tired.
感到疲倦
It has happened with you sometimes.
你偶爾也有這種經驗
But attention should be on the Power,
但你的注意力必須放在這個力量上
attention should be on the connection
放在與它的聯繫上
that we have with this Power.
我們正擁有這力量
Then only. Otherwise you'll be exhausted, naturally.
只能這樣，否則，很自然的你會很累
Everything's so logical, so logical it is.
一切都是那麽有邏輯，很有邏輯的
Thank God, and thank yourself,
感謝天、感謝你自己
thank your luck you're so fortunate
感謝你的運氣
that you are very few who have achieved this connection,
你們是很少數的幸運兒能與這個力量連上
and that you are sucking that power
可以輕易而舉的
within yourself so easily.
吸收這力量
And what are you, why are you behaving
你是甚麼，為甚麼你的行為
like this ordinary street people with your stupid questions?
像普通的街上人那樣，有着愚蠢的問題？
You'll be surprised that Goddess,
你會驚訝地在往世
in previous lives, never spoke so much as I've spoken.
女神從未像我那樣說這麼多話
One or two words were sufficient,
她們只說一兩個字就夠了
like She said, "Hoo!" and killed this, "Ha!" finished that.
像她說：「呵！」就殺掉這個；「吓！」就毀滅那個
All these things She managed
她只說：
only by saying "Hoo, Ha, Hee, Hey".
「呵、吓、嘻、唏！」就令這完蛋
But They never gave Realisation to anyone,
她們從不給人自覺
none of the Incarnations.
沒一位降世神祇給人自覺
They said, "No, no, no, no, no not Me.
她們說：「不、不、不、不、不是我
Not Me, sorry, I'm not going to do it.
不是我，很抱歉，我不會這樣做
They must have seen human beings how stupid they are.
祂們必定是看到人類是那麽愚蠢
"Oh God, nothing. I'm all right.
天啊，沒甚麽，我很妥當
I can go to jungle for fourteen years,
我可以到森林十四年
I can do the driver's job with Arjuna,
我可以與阿周那一起當車夫
or I can get crucified, or I can take poison,
我可以被釘十字架，我可以服毒
but don't tell Me to deal with human beings!
但千萬不要派我去應付人類！
No, no, no, no.
不、不、不、不
Is better to go to a zoo than to go to this."
我寧可去動物園
And that's why none of Them, none of Them,
因此她們沒有一位，沒有一位
and some of Them did not even talk about it,
她們有些甚至沒有提及自覺
thinking that "If We talk, they'll say,
她們以為：「如果我們提及自覺
"Then why not give us the Realisation?"
他們會說︰「為甚麽不給我們自覺？」
None of them.
沒一位給人自覺
So this is the Adi Shakti's compassion, love, and confidence
這就是太初之母的慈悲、愛心和自信
that you should have also confidence.
你們都應該有自信
Not only that I have given you Realisation,
我不只給你們自覺
but I have given you powers
還給你們力量
that you can give Realisations to others.
去給他人自覺
None of these Incarnations did that,
從未有降世神祇做
which you are doing today.
你們正在做的工作
With all Their Powers, They did not do it,
雖然祂們很有力量，卻沒有給人自覺
while you can do it,
你們卻有
despite the fact the instruments are not so strong,
儘管你們的工具不太完備
not so Divine.
不太神聖
But still, still, we have to come up,
雖然如此，我們仍要迎上前
and work out in our own lives
弄清楚你的人生
the priorities that we have.
有那些事情是重要的
For the Gods the priorities were only Divine work,
對諸神來說，神聖的工作是首要的
nothing else.
沒有其他
Nobody took up a job, nobody.
沒有人承擔這任務，沒有人
Nobody went to university, nobody studied.
沒有人上大學或唸書
Only thing They did
他們只做
So you do everything else as work of God
因此，你做的任何事都要視作神的工作
and that's how the energy will flow into you.
那麽能量便會流向你
When you start doing the work of God,
當你開始做神的工作
everything you do becomes work of God
你做的一切工作都變成神的工作
in the sense that you do the work of God, you decide,
即是說，當你決定
"I'm going to do the work of God," then God takes over.
「我要做神的工作。」神就會接手
He does all the rest of the things,
做其餘的事情
I hope you understand this, try.
我希望你們明白
Try.
試試吧！
Have confidence.
要有信心
And also thank God there is Someone, like your Mother,
也要感謝神能有一位像母親的人
Who can tell you what's wrong with you.
告訴你你哪裏出問題
Thank God!
感謝天！
Even your mothers didn't tell you what was wrong,
即使你的母親也沒有告訴你哪裏出錯
because they were so frightened of you.
因為她們都害怕你
And don't say then - then, when you say something,
不要說然後…然後，當你說了一些話
"Mother, my heart catches."
母親，我的心輪受感染
I mean, what can you do, then?
我的意思是你能做甚麼？
If you understand that this is for your improvement
如果你明白我這麼做是為了令你能有所改進
then you'll work it out.
那麽你就能成就到
But I don't think it is so much of a mental understanding,
我不認為這是思維上的理解
but it's the understanding of a higher level,
是更高層次的理解
where it becomes just part and parcel of your awareness.
它成為你的感知的一部分
"How can it be wrong?
它怎會出錯？
It's all has to be good for me, everything is good for me."
所有都是為我着想，為我著想
Last but not the least,
還有一點
one must understand that as all these seven chakras
你們要明白，我清理的這七個輪穴
I am working on are in a collective way held
都是集體地在宇宙層面
by Me in My Virata.
由我保管
The quality of Viratangana is that,
Viratangana的品質是
that She creates this universal awareness within us,
她在我們內裏創造宇宙大我的感知
the collectivity.
即是集體
And, if you do not realize that in modern times
若你們不知道，在現代
we are in a spiritual path in a collective way only.
我們集體地走在同一靈性的道路上
This is what it is.
就是這樣
Because we have reached to the state of Sahasrara
由於我們已到達頂輪的階段
and here we have to have a collective working only,
在這裡我們只能集體地成就
there's no other way out!
沒有其他途徑
This is what is to be absolutely realized.
你們要完全明白
Anybody who tries to harm the collectivity by bad behaviour,
任何人以壞行為或
or by anything,
任何事情傷害集體
will be thrown out, no doubt,
都會被趕走，這是毋庸置疑的
but also will fall into wrong hands.
也會跌落壞人的手中
So collectivity is the work of Adi Shakti.
集體是太初之母的工作
Because at the Sahasrara,
因為在頂輪
at the Sahasrara,
在頂輪
at the Sahasrara is the rule of Virata.
宇宙大我掌管頂輪
And the Power of Virata is the Viratangana.
而宇宙大我的力量是Viratangana
Is the One Who does collectivity.
是它成就集體的
This is the most important point we must know
我們要明白最重要的是
if we cannot be collective - because of anything,
如果我們不合群---可能出於任何原因
jealousy maybe, inferiority complex maybe, any,
或許出於嫉妒、自卑，或任何
anything which is coming from behind
隱秘的原因
like a worm crawling up -then,
像毛蟲般爬進來
know that something wrong with you,
我們便知道錯在自己
nothing wrong with the collectivity.
而不是集體
Don't criticize the collectivity,
不要批評集體
till I Myself find it out, and I'll put it right.
我自會找出集體的問題，把它糾正
Keep to the collectivity, wisely
要參與集體
and earnestly and try to keep the collectivity together.
有智慧和誠懇地維繫集體
Try to help to keep the people collective to enjoy together.
讓大家合群，享受集體
Don't criticize each other;
不要互相批評
only criticize yourself.
只批評自己
If you are in the habit of criticism,
如果你慣於批評人
better criticize yourself.
請改為批評自己吧
It's better, because these are habits also.
這樣比較好，因為這也是習慣
People, specially I've seen people in the West,
人們，尤其是西方人
they react to everything.
他們對任何事都有反應
If they see this carpet,
若他們看到這地毯
"Uh! I don't like it!"
噢！我不喜歡它！
But this is not yours, not made for you,
它並非屬於你的，不是為你而造的
what have you got to do with it?
它跟你有甚麼關係？
what's the question?
有甚麼問題？
It's lying here, why should you be so upset about it?
它鋪放在這裡，你為甚麼要不高興？
"I don't like that person! I don't like that dress!"
我不喜歡這個人！我不喜歡這條裙子！
Who are you?
你是誰？
"I don't like."
我不喜歡
This is not allowed in Sahaja Yoga - "I don't like."
在霎哈嘉瑜伽是不容許「我不喜歡」
There is a way of saying things.
這是一種說話的方式
But there is no need to say anything whatsoever.
不管如何，其實沒有需要說甚麼
So all this kind of bumptiousness
這種狂妄自大
and showing off is against collectivity.
是不利於集體的
Then there are some other stupid type of people
我看到有些愚蠢的人
who are always there to take My photograph I've seen.
總想替我拍照
You tell them, "Don't be so forward, don't go."
你告訴他們：「不要走上前，不要。」
"No, I will, I don't do this, I am not. Finished!"
不，我要，不做不成！」我不要。就這樣
But they, some of them are really confirmed,
他們有些實在是蠢人
certified I think, stupid, idiots.
確實地，無藥可救
They cannot be improved.
不能改善
But I told you that don't make them your ideals,
我告訴你千萬不要以他們為榜樣，
don't follow their images.
也不要有樣學樣
So then, we come to this point,
跟著，我們來到這一點
that Adi Shakti's work is the most important work
太初之母的工作是
in the whole creation.
整個創造最重要的
All right killing the demons was over,
降魔伏妖已經完成
Done!
已經完成
Saraswati's work was done, She created dinosaurs so what?
莎維德麗的工作亦已經完成；她創造了恐龍，那又如何？
Mahalakshmi's work was done.
摩訶拉希什米的工作已經完成
She brought you to human level, all right, so what?
她把你們帶到人類的層面，對，那又如何？
But the climax is now that you have got your Realsation,
現在是高潮，你得到自覺
that you have got this special quality,
得到這特別的素質
that now you have entered into the Kingdom of God.
你已經進入神的國度
So now behave yourself.
所以你的言行舉止必須檢點
And also you must have that dignity to know that,
也要有尊嚴去明白
now we have entered into the Kingdom of God.
你們已經進入神的國度
I've seen, once I was going to see the President of India.
有一次我要與印度總統會面
But to Me he was another human being,
他對我來說與其他人沒有分別
I mean, it never goes into My head this presidentship
我從沒有想到他
and all that.
總統的身份
I was walking up,
我在走路時
and those who were walking with Me became very conscious,
與我同行的人突然變得很拘謹
you see, like this.
像這樣
I said, "What's the matter with these people?
我說：「這些人出了甚麼問題？
Have they seen some ghost or something?"
他們見到鬼還是甚麼？
Just going on the steps.
走上梯級
And they were some people standing with, you see,
有些守衛拿着矛和一些
spears and things as guards,
甚麽東西站在梯級上
or whatever it is. So, I was just laughing at all that.
不管如何，我感到很可笑
But these people became very conscious.
這些人變得很拘謹
When you are entering into the Kingdom of God,
當你們進入神的國度時
how conscious you should be about your behaviour!
你有多在意自己的言行舉止？
How you should be,
你要怎樣
how you should behave?
你的行為要怎樣？
Just feel the uniqueness of your personality
只需要感受一下
that you are in the Kingdom of God already.
你已經在神的國度的獨特之處
Just feel it.
只要感受一下
If you can feel only that,
如果你能感受到
then you will know what a place of pride you have got
你就會知道，你取得一個多麼光榮的位置
and how dignified you should be.
你應要有多尊貴
How beautiful you should be.
多美麗
How neat and clean and sweet you should be.
多整齊清潔可愛
How much maryadas you must know, everything.
你必須認識要有多少份際
And when you will realize that now you are the coveted,
當你知道你是人們夢寐以求的
or we can say the highest citizens of the Kingdom of God,
或可以說你是神的國度中最高的國民
then you have to prove that you have really realized it.
你便要證明你真的明白
That you really feel that.
真的感受到
And you should feel extremely joyful, happy.
你應該感到極度喜樂歡欣
Like yesterday, at the smallest thing everybody's laughing
好像昨天，你們像街上的人
like the other street people.
為一些小事大笑
It's not the Sahaja Yoga.
這並非霎哈嘉瑜伽
If there was a big joke or something, laugh,
如果有大笑話之類的，儘管笑吧
otherwise somebody is talking, you're laughing.
要不然有人說話，你只在笑
I was surprised, you're Sahaja Yogis.
我會很驚訝，你們是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Think of saints doing this, will they do?
想想聖人會不會這麼？
You are saints;
你們是聖人
you are munindras with smanana,
你們以smanana 成為munindras
with your meditation you have become the kings.
透過靜坐你們都成為王者
How can you behave in a indignified manner?
你們的行為怎能不尊貴？
Now, try to assume your position!
現在，要做好本份
Try to feel it.
嘗試感受它
Yesterday, of course, when the last song started,
昨天，在唱最後一首歌時
it did penetrate, I know, into many souls, to many hearts,
我知道它滲入感動很多人的心靈
that unique joy, which we call as Nirananda.
這種我們稱為nirananda的獨特喜樂
I did feel it yesterday.
我昨日真的感覺到它
But keep it up, it's just to be kept very safely
要讓它繼續，要把它好好
into your Khumbas, is the Kundalini.
收藏在你們的寶瓶(khumbas)，即靈量裏
And She is the One Who has come up.
是她要昇上來
So, My idea was that
今天我想
where the Kundalini resides,
靈量住在哪裏
but the Khumba becomes like a flower pot.
khumba變得像花盆
It's like that, that has happened
就像這樣，事情已經發生
and then it can also, as somebody said that,
也會繼續發生，就如有人說：
"Mother these flower pots also can become table lamps."
母親，這些花盆可以變成枱燈
I said, "See, now, you've said it!"
我說：「看，你也這麼說！」
So the Khumba becoming flowers, and flowers becoming light,
所以這寶瓶變成花兒；花兒變成光
and the lights with fragrance!
有香氣的光
I hope you'll understand My vision
希望你們明白我的願景
and you'll stand by Me,
支持我
you'll come up to that.
你們會成就到
I depend on you entirely for My vision.
我完全依靠你們實現我的願景
We have to change this whole world into a beautiful place.
我們要把這個世界變成美麗的地方
Now for that not much sacrifice is needed.
為此不需要犧牲太多
You're already blessed, you don't have to do much,
你們已經受到祝福，不用做太多
only thing is keep your attention on the source of Power.
只要把注意力保持在力量的源頭
May God bless you.
願神祝福你們
Ah? Thank you.
謝謝
Mathias says, "We promise." You all say that.
馬天娜說：「我們承諾。」你們都說吧
Thank you very much.
十分感謝你們
You should all write some of the miracles,
你要把奇蹟
Like we went to Paris,
例如有一次我們去巴黎
and they wanted to buy some saris for the ladies here,
他們想為哪裏的女士買紗麗
and nowhere we could get anything forty-five inches.
但沒有辦法找到有四十五吋長的布匹
Either it was thirty-six inches,
不是三十六吋
or it was fifty-eight inches.
就是五十八吋
Then while going in the car, suddenly I said, "Now stop!"
當我們坐在車子裡，我突然叫車停下來
They said, "What Mother? In the street?" I said,
他們說：「母親甚麼事？在街上？」
"In the street only there is somebody selling the saris."
我說：「有人在街上售賣紗麗。」
And we got them.
我們便買到想要的紗麗
Another - you have seen already
另一次，你們在
in the Ganapatipule Ganesh Puja,
伽納帕蒂普雷的格涅沙崇拜
that how we had a jackpot for your presents.
都看過我們怎樣為禮物贏得奬金
You used to always bring presents, very expensive and
你們時常送我昂貴
wasting so much money.
浪費很多金錢
And how we got this, just the same way.
我們怎樣取得它，也是一樣
Coming from the airport I just said,
從機場來時我說
"Now there's something here!"
這兒有些東西
They said, "Mother, nothing there's a shop."
他們說：「母親，只有一家商店。」
I said, "Let's go and see!"
我說：「進去看看！」
Just we went round, and there all this things at a song.
我們進去轉了一圈，哪裏的貨品都很便宜
Now same thing happened in America,
同樣事情在美國也發生
I went down, I said, "The China is in trouble,
我坐下說：「中國有麻煩，
let's buy something Chinese."
我們買些中國貨吧
So we went to the Chinese shops;
我們走進一家中國商店
And I turned the corner and I said,
我走到一個街角說：
"All right let me go into a little lane,"
讓我們走進這小巷吧
and there it was, a shop which sold everything very cheaply,
哪裡有一家商店，賣的東西都比
for again forty percent less.
其他商店便宜四成
Something has to do with forty percent.
全都與十分之四有關
And just by chance only, I think,
我想只是偶然
hundred meters away they were selling at five times more,
在一百米之外的商店便以五、
six times more. And why it is?
六倍價錢出售
So now you also try.
怎會這樣？你們都可以試試；
But desire should be pure, understanding should be pure.
但你的願望必須純粹，理解也必須純粹
So I just thought that these Sahaja Yogis
我只在想這些霎哈嘉瑜伽士
spend so much money, waste so much money,
花掉很多錢，浪費很多錢
and get something which is of no value.
去購買這些無價值的物品
Because all the presents you give Me, actually,
你們送給我的所有禮物，我其實
I have been asking them to stop it, and stop it and stop it.
已經要求他們不要再送了，停止再送了
Now from individual,
現在送禮從個人層面
we have brought it to the level of national.
提升到國家層面
But even in the national,
即使是國家層面
I think we now should just have no national,
我認為我們不應該再分國家
if you people agree.
你們明年可以這樣
But whatever it is,
不管如何，無論你給我甚麽
I'm not going to give it to anyone,
也不會轉贈他人
it should be such that we can keep
我們要保存它們
for the progeny to see what you have given.
好讓子孫後代看到你們給我怎樣的禮物
It is the value of this is this,
它們的價值就在於此
not the value how much you spent.
不在於你花費多少
So, there is no need for individually
完全沒有需要個別
to give Me any presents at all, I know you love Me.
送我禮物，我知道你愛我
And now, I don't know, I've been telling the leaders
我也不清楚，我已經告訴領袖們
that "Please don't ask for the national present,
個別國家請勿再送禮物了
now don't waste money."
不要浪費金錢
But I don't know if they are not yet agreeing,
我不知道他們是否還未同意
and if they agree we can stop this.
若他們同意就可以停止送禮
And have even international present
即使是國際的禮物
which could be also brought down.
也可以減少
Because you know, I don't need anything.
你們都知道，我甚麽也不需要
But it works.
可是它會成就
It works.
會成就的
Like I said, "You give Me ivory this time,"
像我說：「這次你們給我象牙吧。」
and ivory was so very expensive, everything,
象牙是很昂貴的
again that also we found it at a such a cheap place.
我們再次能以很便宜的價錢買到象牙
And once you gave Me the ivory,
當你給我象牙
you won't believe, I read in the newspaper
你不會相信，我從報章中
now in America it is three dollars per kilo.
現在在美國卻只售三元一公斤
It's true or not?
真的嗎？
And also the idea is to give more encouragement
這樣做是為了鼓勵
to handicrafts and to art,
手工藝和藝術
because so many times I have told that
我說過很多次
a little of a clay you can take and make it
你們只要用一點兒黏土，便可以製造
So, why should we exhaust this Mother Earth?
那麽，為甚麼還要耗用大地之母的資源？
Why not we have few artistic nice things,
與其擁有很多東西
instead of having so many things?
倒不如只擁有少量但有藝術價值的物品？
But if you go in the shops now you don't get anything.
現在，你們不會在商店買到甚麽
You don't get silk, you cannot get this,
你買不到絲綢，買不到這些
you cannot get that.
買不到那些
So difficult to get anything natural,
很難找到一些天然物料的物品
because people have only making unnatural things.
因為大家都製造不天然的貨品
Whatever it is, in that also you should create beauty.
無論是甚麼，你都要創出美麗
If you start creating beauty,
若你能創出美麗
then we'll try to preserve it
我們便要保存它
and use it sparingly instead of having thousands
珍惜它，這比擁有千件無用的
of nonsensical things, everything disposable.
可即棄的東西好
After sometime,
遲早會有
we'll have to have human beings who are disposal.
可扔掉的人類
We'll have to dispose them off.
我們要扔掉他們
How will they live on this earth
如果我們不懂
if we do not understand that
怎樣運用有限的資源生活
we have to live on this earth with its limitations.
怎能繼續在地球生存？
See, I've been telling you, many times,
我已經多次告訴你們
take to artistic things, take to handmade things,
要多用富藝術性，人手造的東西
more to handmade.
多些人手造的
Don't go too much to this.
但不要過份
At least, even if you have to buy something
最起碼，即使你要買
which is, say, artificial,
非天然的東西
So, the once you have a great desire
當你們有這個偉大的願望
- today is the day they want in the whole world to pray
今天他們想全世界都
for the preservation of Mother Earth,
祈求保護大地之母
that's why I started this topic,
因此我開展這個話題
that we should pray that we all should develop art,
我們應祈求能為自己發展藝術
develop for ourselves, give as presents to others,
作為給別人的禮物，也要使用藝術家
and also to use artistic things, made of artist.
創造富藝術性的物品
We can have few things,
我們只需要擁有很少
but artistic which expresses art.
但富藝術性
Not cheap things.
而不是低俗的物品
In the whole of France
在法國我看到
what I saw was that into everything this plastics has crept
這些人造物料不知不覺蔓延一切
in whether it is cotton, whether it is silk,
無論是綿質、絲質
whether it is wool.
或羊毛物品中
It can enter into everywhere
除了人腦外，
So, whatever it is,
無論買甚麼
in that also see that you buy artistic things,
要買富藝術感
not plain, horrible, cheap things.
而非平凡、可怕和低俗的物品
All right? So this is what we have to today,
明白嗎？今天就說到這裏
also, you have to pray to Me when you are doing puja,
當你們做崇拜時，請向我祈求
that "Oh, Mother, Oh Mother, please save our earth,
母親啊，請拯救我們的地球
and give people wisdom,
給人智慧
that they should behave themselves.
好使他們檢點自己
And they should be conscious".
他們應要當心
And every Sahaja Yogi should be conscious
每個霎哈嘉瑜伽士都要當心
about how much energy he is using of electricity,
用多少電力
of telephones, or of water or of anything.
電話、水或其他
We have to be frugal about it.
我們要節約
If we do not take the responsibility of these things,
假如我們不負起這個責任
then it will not penetrate anywhere else.
它是不會滲透到其他地方
It is for you to do it.
這是你們要做的
You have to take it up in your everyday life
你們要在日常生活中養成節約的習慣
as a part and parcel of your life
這個習慣要成為你生活的一部分
that you try to save the energy of this Mother Earth.
儘量節省大地之母的資源
Is very important.
這是非常重要的
So today is the day they have sent a special prayer,
今天他們送上特別的禱告
of course it's done by some churches of whatever it is,
當然，那是從教會之類的地方而來
but I think is a good day,
但我認為這是一個好日子
because they must have thought today
因為他們一定想到
is the day of the Goddess,
這是女神的日子
and that's how they've asked for.
因此他們作出這個請求
May God bless you.
願神祝福你們